Guide to the Henri Chopin Papers GEN MSS 868
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize, 154121; 1 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
  - Chopin, Henri (from Series V), 1980, undated; 154123; 2 Folders (Box 90 (Oversize))
  - Corfou, Michel (from Series V), undated; 154122 (Box 90 (Oversize))
- Broadsides, 154089; (31 broadside folders)
  - Photographs of artwork (from Series III), 1994; 154120 (Box 91 (Broadside))
  - The London Underground (from Series III), undated; 154119 (Box 92 (Broadside))
  - Empreintes sur les Andes (from Series III), 1992; 154118 (Box 93 (Broadside))
  - Spaghetti Decorated Ltd or Desdemona solid (from Series III), 1974; 154117 (Box 94 (Broadside))
  - On recherche les tueurs (from Series III), 1967; 154116 (Box 95 (Broadside))
  - Henri Chopin: Graphpoemachines (from Series III), 2006; 154115 (Box 96 (Broadside))
  - Batbedat, Vincent (from Series IV), 1990; 154114 (Box 97 (Broadside))
  - Chaminade, Jacques (from Series IV), undated; 154113 (Box 98 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated; 154112 (Box 99 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated; 154111 (Box 100 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated; 154110 (Box 101 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated; 154109 (Box 102 (Broadside))
  - Hobba, Leigh (from Series IV), 1991; 154108 (Box 103 (Broadside))
  - Hughes, Patrick (from Series IV), 1974; 154107 (Box 104 (Broadside))
  - Janicot, Françoise (from Series IV), 1963-1964; 154106 (Box 105 (Broadside))
  - Jorn, Asger (from Series IV), 1980; 154105 (Box 106 (Broadside))
  - Leonard, Tom (from Series IV), undated; 154104 (Box 107 (Broadside))
  - Rougier, Vincent (from Series IV), 1991; 154103 (Box 108 (Broadside))
  - Rühm, Gerhard (from Series IV), 1985-1986, undated; 154102 (Box 109 (Broadside))
  - Xenakis, Constantin (from Series IV), 1983-1986; 154101 (Box 110 (Broadside))
  - Aubertin, Bernard (from Series IV), 1969-1984; 154100 (Box 111 (Broadside))
  - Charmoy, Cozette de (from Series IV), 154099 (Box 112 (Broadside))
  - Dufrêne, François (from Series IV), 154098 (Box 113 (Broadside))
  - Furnival, John (from Series IV), 154097 (Box 114 (Broadside))
  - Gette, Paul-Armand (from Series IV), 154096 (Box 115 (Broadside))
  - Gisiger, Hansjörg (from Series IV), undated; 154095 (Box 116 (Broadside))
  - Peire, Luc (from Series IV), 154094 (Box 117 (Broadside))
  - Phillips, Tom (from Series IV), 154093 (Box 118 (Broadside))
  - Unsorted (from Series IV), 154092 (Box 119 (Broadside))
  - Posters (from Series VIII), 1967-2006; 154091 (Box 120 (Broadside))
  - Posters (from Series VIII), 1967-2006; 154090 (Box 121 (Broadside))
- Restricted Fragile Material, 154087; 0.21 Linear Feet (1 box)
  - Computer disks, 154088; (3 computer disks) (Box 122)
    Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - SAPRITHÈQUE CD 01 1999, 2011-genm-47008-0001; 1 CD-Rs; 733675868 bytes 733.68 Megabytes (Box 122)
    - henri chopin "Croquis 1952-54" (coll. Acquaviva-Faustino), 2011-genm-47008-0002; 1 CD-Rs; 43185072 bytes 43.19 Megabytes. (Box 122)
    - pour Henri Chopin, mon ami! frédéric acquaviva musique acatalentique (2007, 5') (voix J'.LP), 2011-genm-47008-0003; 1 CD-Rs; 63955584 bytes 63.96 Megabytes. (Box 122)
- September 2013 Acquisition, 1963-2007; 9; 680050; 1.13 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
  - Original works, 1963-1983; 680059
    - Henri Chopin: "Pensées sur la création," manuscript and rosewood box, 1967 September 20; 680051; (2 folders) (Box 129)
    - Henri Chopin: "Hommage à Jean Ratcliffe," dactyle poem, signed, 1983 January 25; 680053 (Box 129)
    - Aubertin: "Prix d'Excellence: Madame Aubertin de Paris - pour mon ami Henri Chopin," book composed of drawings and collages, undated; 680069 (Box 130)
    - John Furnival: "Semiotic drawing. Plakat 3", 1965 November; 680055 (Box 129)
    - Leo Breuer: "Bois original," with dedication to Henri Chopin, 1963; 680056 (Box 129)
    - Stephan Themerson: "Brother Francis' Lambchops," operatic score, circa 1972; 680057 (Box 129)
  - Chopin correspondence, 1963-2007; 680060
    - Correspondence, 1970-2006; 680061; (2 folders) (Box 129)
      Includes correspondence by: Roberto Altmann, Gianni Bertini, Camus, Luciano Caruso, Bob Cobbing, Francis Edeline, Pierre Garnier, Ken Gill, Raoul Hausmann, Alain Jejou, G.X. Juppiter-Larsen, David Miller, Herman Sabbe, Daniel Sotiaux, Larry Wendt, Alexandre Yterce, Nicolas Zurbrugg, and Paul [?].
    - "Henri Chopin", 1982-1983; 680062 (Box 129)
      Includes: Texte sur Armand Schwerner (1983 December 2-3), L'idée de faire des films (1982 June 27), and Résumé d'une démarche.
    - "Responses To", 1982-2007; 680063 (Box 129)
      Includes correspondence to: Frédérique Devaux (1982 June 7), Monsieur Lucken (1998 February 8), and Guy Shraenen (2007 November 04).
    - "Letters To", 1983-1984; 680064 (Box 129)
      Includes correspondence to: Amis de l'ADAP (1983 January 29), Marc Malfant (1984 June 22), and Maison des Artistes (1984 November 20).
    - "Wishes", 1966-2006; 680065 (Box 129)
      Includes cards and mail art from: Gianni Bertini (2003), William Burroughs (1970), Bob Cobbing (1970), John Furnival (1966), Brion Gisin, Key Sato (1968), and Francine Urbin Choffray (2006).
    - "Various", 1963-1976; 680066; (2 folders) (Box 131)
      Contains: a cocktail invitation from Pierre Albert-Birot (1965), an original stencil on ceramic tile from Béguier (1966), a drawing dedicated to Henri Chopin by Marcelle Cahn (1963), and drawings by Bettina [?] (1976).
  - Writings, 1967; 680078
    - Henri Chopin - Gianni Bertini: Bo de l'Air," manuscript, 1967; 680070 (Box 132)
  - Artwork, 1958-1975; 680071
    - "J'ai assis la Beauté mes genoux...," by Henri Chopin, collage, undated; 680072 (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - "The New Mona Lisa," by Henri Chopin, framed print, circa 1975; 680074 (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - "Le dernier sonnet du monde", by Henri Chopin, framed poem, 1958 May 19-20; 680076 (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - "Je", by Henri Chopin, framed, 1969 February; 680077 (Box 134 (Oversize))
- August 2015 Acquisition, 1965-1987; X; 0.21 Linear Feet (1 box)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Philippe Luigi, 2015.
  Correspondence, writings, and printed material relating to Henri Chopin. Correspondents include Henryk Berlewi, Suzanne Bernard, Charles Bukowski, Georges Charbonnier, Andrew Cozens of Platform magazine, Gaston Criel, Marc Dachy, Stanisław Dróżdż, Nikolas Einhorn of S Press Tonbandverlag, Michael Gibbs of Kontexts Publications, Michel Giroud, and Gérald Gassiot-Talabot.
  - Correspondence, writings, and printed material, 1965-1987 (Box 135)